Byzantine Institute, Inc. Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection. The Byzantine Institute and Dumbarton Oaks Fieldwork Records and Papers, ca. late 1920s-2000s: Finding Aid
Image Collections and Fieldwork Archives, Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection
- Fieldwork Papers, 1920s -2000s, MS.BZ.004-02; 46 boxes including 494 folders; 29 boxes including 29 photo albums; 20+ oversize files; 26 boxes of backlog materials; 2 boxes including 14 folders of accumulated research materials by ICFA staff
  - Fieldwork Notebooks and Research Notes, ca. 1929-1970s, MS.BZ.004-02-01; 30 boxes containing 299 folders
    - Red Sea Monasteries, Egypt, ca. late 1920s-1940s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01; 2 boxes containing 34 folders
      - Texts from various sources, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-009; 1 folder; Former processor noted the initials "T.W." on the back of each paper.
        Contains: “The Life of Apa Cyrus;” “The Life of Apa Onnophrios The Anchorite;” “Four Coptic Monasteries in the Natron Valley;” “The Account of the Pakhomian Rules (from Ladeuze);” “Monasticism in Egypt;” and a copy of “The Architecture of Christian Egypt (Introduction)”
      - Copies of texts from various sources, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-010; 1 folder
        Contains: “The Life of Apa Cyrus;” “The Life of Apa Onnophrios The Anchorite;” “Four Coptic Monasteries in the Natron Valley;” “Account of the Pakhomian Rules (from Ladeuze);” and “Monasticism in Egypt”
      - Typewritten text: "St. Antony's Monastery" and a list of paintings, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-011; 1 folder
      - Notebook with sketches, transcriptions of inscriptions, and a list of photographs, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-012; 1 folder
      - Transcriptions of inscriptions in Greek, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-013; 1 folder
        Contains: “The Haikal at St. Anthony;” “Inscriptions on the E. wall of the Haikal (Representations of the Patriarchs);” and “Church of St. Anthony Haikal E. Wall”
      - Transcriptions of inscriptions in Greek, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-014; 1 folder
        Contains: “Niche of the Haikal;” “Church of St. Anthony, Two angels in the arch leading to the passage before the Haikal;” “The ‘Resurrection’ above the door leading to the Haikal;” “Monastery of St. Anthony, Main Church;” “Passage before the Haikal, St. George” and “Rep. of Prophets in the arch leading to the Haikal”
      - Transcriptions of inscriptions in Greek from "Chapel of the Monastery of St. Anthony", late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-015; 1 folder
      - Descriptions, notes and transcriptions of inscriptions for the saints depicted in St. Anthony, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-016; 1 folder
        Includes transcriptions of inscriptions for the “Saints in the Narthex of the church of St. Anthony” and “Resurrection of O. L. in the church of St. Anthony”
      - Transcriptions of inscriptions from the church of St. Anthony in the narthex, Main Church, Small Chapel, and Haikal, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-017; 1 folder
      - Notes and correspondence, 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-018; 1 folder
        Includes correspondence between J. L. Capes and Thomas Whittemore regarding James Burton's notes, March 12, 1932
        J.L. Capes was possibly a scholar who assisted Thomas Whittemore, ca. 1930s, on his research of James Burton's trip to the Red Sea Monasteries
        Capes, J.L.
      - Notebooks with notes and transcriptions of inscriptions in German and English, 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-019; 1 folder; A note inside one of the notebooks states: “Piankoff, Oct 1931 Sts Anthony & Paul notebooks.” The calendars inside the notebook are for the years 1930 and 1931.
      - Piankoff, Alexandre, typewritten manuscript:" St. Anthony I History (duplicate)", 1930-1940, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-020; 1 folder; A note on the cover page states: “by Piankoff ca. 1930-40 / well pd. by B.I. for it – rcv’d more than any other of DL staff.” Also, on page 10 of the manuscript, there is a typed notation “ANP/VNR” and pages 32-41 are missing. The initials likely refer to Alexandre Piankoff and Vladimir Rayevsky.
      - Piankoff, Alexandre, copy of a typewritten manuscript:" St. Anthony I History (duplicate)", 1930-1940, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-021; 1 folder
      - Hand-written transcription:"Monastery of Saint-Anthony: Inscriptions (copy of AP's note-book)", May 1946, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-022; 1 folder; A note on the cover page states: “made by B.E. in May 1946 / original sent to A.P. Cairo May 27th 1946.” The initials likely refer to Boris Ermoloff and Alexandre Piankoff.
      - Miscellaneous notes and references relating to Coptic Art and rider saints, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-023; 1 folder
        Contains: sketches, notes, a newspaper clipping, a pamphlet in Arabic, and a notebook in various languages containing Coptic words translated into German
      - Miscellaneous notes and transcriptions relating to lamps, St. Mercurius, and other topics, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-024; 1 folder
        Includes sketches and transcriptions of quotations from Plato's dialogues: Meno, Timeus, and Theaetetus
      - Copy of transcription: "Le Roman d'Eudoxie soeur de Constantin", Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-025; 1 folder
      - Extracts and notes from various sources, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-026; 1 folder
      - Notes and transcriptions of texts in French and Russian, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-027; 1 folder
      - Colored drawing of a Turkish "Skorochod" in Russian, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-028; 1 folder; Transcription of Russian is “скороходъ.”
      - Catalog of books in Arabic from Library at St. Paul's Monastery, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-029; 1 folder
      - Lists of photographs for the first and second expeditions at the Red Sea Monasteries, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-030; 1 folder
        Lists of photographs taken by Kazazian. Also includes a list for negatives of the watercolor copies of the wall paintings executed by Vladimir Netchetailov.
        Kazazian
        For related photographs, see Subgroup 2, Series 4, Subseries 1, "Original Photographs" and Subseries 2, "Duplicate Photographs." For the original watercolors, see Subgroup 2, Series 5, Subseries 2, "Oversize: Large."
      - Typewritten text: "The Riding Sun-God Sculpture", Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-031; 1 folder
      - Hand-written and typewritten texts: "Resurrection" by Alexandre Piankoff and Vladimir Rayevsky, Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-032; 1 folder
      - Typewritten text: "Persian Lustred Ware", Undated, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-033; 1 folder
      - Reports, notes, and excerpts from texts relating to Carthage, Tunisia, Early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-034; 1 folder
        Includes "CRYSTAL OBJECTS DISCOVERED AT CARTHAGE" by Alexandre Piankoff.
    - Fieldwork Notebooks, Hagia Sophia, Istanbul, Turkey, 1932-1940, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02; 15 boxes including 163 folders
      Notebooks maintained by fieldworkers to record daily progress on work at Hagia Sophia between 1932-1940.
      - "Constantinople" and Sketch of "LUNETTA CENTRALE PRIMA DELLA PULITURA", March 1932, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-035/036; 2 folders
        Descriptions and illustrations of lunettes and crosses
      - Kluge, Nicholas, and Whittemore, Thomas, notebook: "Damascus Sept. 9th 1932", September 9, 1932, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-037; 1 folder
      - Coe, M., "NOTES ON THE VESTIBULE MOSAIC", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-038; 1 folder
        M. Coe was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1933-1934
        Coe, M.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Mr. Gregory's Diary of works in St. Sophia", April 22, 1933 - November 14, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-039; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Diary of Work in St. Sophia"
        Work conducted at the narthex and southwest vestibule. Notebook was signed by Richard A. Gregory on November 19, 1933.
        Gregory, Richard A.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "DAILY JOURNAL: MOSQUE OF St. Sophia", April 22, 1933 - November 14, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-040; 1 folder
        Work conducted at the narthex and southwest vestibule. Typed version was signed by Richard A. Gregory on November 19, 1933.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes taken while working on the Vestibule Panel and general notes of work in Narthex and Barrel vaulting", August 8, 1933 - November 18, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-041; 1 folder
      - Gregory, Richard A., "GENERAL NOTES of work in the Narthex and Barrel Vaulting", August 8, 1933 - November 18, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-042; 1 folder
        Refers to fixing plaster, installing cramps, and taking measurements and photographs. Typed version was signed by Richard A. Gregory on November 19, 1933.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Descriptive Report on Bays of Narthex", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-043; 1 folder
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "Description of the Vestibule Panel", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-044/045; 2 folders
        Descriptions of the mosaic cubes in the figures of the Virgin, Justinian, and Constantine
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "Kluge's notes on Central Lunette and Vestibule Panel", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-046; 1 folder
      - Lye, Albert H., "Daily Journal: Mosque of St. Sophia", May 15, 1933 - November 18, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-047; 1 folder
        Notebook was signed by Albert H. Lye on November 19, 1933
        Albert H. Lye was a British mosaicist employed by the Byzantine Institute in Hagia Sophia
        Lye, Albert H.
      - Lye, Albert H., "Daily Journal: Mosque of St. Sophia", May 15, 1933 - November 18, 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-048; 1 folder
        Typed version was signed by Albert H. Lye on November 19, 1933
      - Lye, Albert H., "Summary of A.H. Lye's description of the Vestibule Panel: SECOND SEASON OF WORK", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-049; 1 folder; It is not clear if the notes came from Richard A. Gregory or W. J. Gregory. ICFA staff believes that this summary is part of the Hagia Sophia preliminary reports.
        Summary also includes notes from "Mr. Gregory's book"
      - Lye, Albert H., "Note-Book No. I", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-050; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 4
        Contains charcoal sketches and notes
      - Lye, Albert H., "Note-Book No. II", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-051; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 4
      - Lye, Albert H., "Note-Book No. III", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-052; 1 folder with notebook 3 of 4
      - Lye, Albert H., "Note-Book No. IV", 1933, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-053; 1 folder with notebook 4 of 4
        Relates to a second interview between Thomas Whittemore and the Turkish authorities
      - Adli Bey, "Paints, Plans, Sketches, [and] Drafts", 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-054; 1 folder; Bey refers to "Mr." Adli Bey was possibly the author of this notebook.
        Measurements of Hagia Sophia (e.g. south barrel and vaulting)
      - Flockton, George H., "Diary Original", April 25, 1934 - November 25, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-055; 1 folder
        Work conducted on the lunette mosaic of the Virgin Mary flanked by Justinian and Constantine at the southwest vestibule
        George Henry Flockton was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1934-1939
        Flockton, George Henry
      - Flockton, George H., "Dairy of Work, [duplicate]",, April 25, 1934 - November 20, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-056; 1 folder
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Diary of Work at St. Sophia I", April 22, 1934 - September 20, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-057; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule and narthex. Notebook was signed by Richard A. Gregory on September 20, 1934.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Diary of Work at St. Sophia II", September 22, 1934 - November 19, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-058; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Work conducted in the southwest pier of the south gallery
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Diary of Work at St. Sophia: Vestibule Panel", April 22, 1934 - November 19, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-059; 1 folder
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes of Work at St. Sophia I", April 22, 1934 - July 12, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-060; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 3
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule. Notebook was signed by Richard A. Gregory on July 12, 1934.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes of work in South Gallery II", July 14, 1934 - September 20, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-061; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 3
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule, narthex, and south gallery. Notebook was signed by Richard A. Gregory on September 20, 1934.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Notebook: Diary of work in the South Gallery, B-Bay III", September 22, 1934 - November 19, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-062; 1 folder with notebook 3 of 3; Notebook contains a piece of aluminium foil.
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Measurements taken in vestibule", Unknown, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-063; 1 folder
        Richard A. Gregory was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1933-1939
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Photographs taken revised notebook", November 7, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-064; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Photographs taken in 1934 at the Mosque of St. Sophia"
        Descriptions of each photograph
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Diary & Observations I", April 22, 1934 - September 23, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-065; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 3
        Work and observations in the southwest vestibule and south gallery
        William John Gregory was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1933-1939
        Gregory, William John
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Diary & Observations II", August 9, 1934 - September 23, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-066; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 3
        Work and observations in the south gallery, Bay B and D, and barrel vaulting
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Diary & Observations III", September 23, 1934 - November 19, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-067; 1 folder with notebook 3 of 3
        Work conducted in the south gallery, east wall, and southwest vestibule
      - Gregory, William John, "Diary of Work at St. Sophia", Aprill 22, 1934 - September 10, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-068; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Work conducted in the narthex, southwest vestibule, and south gallery: installing wooden and steel scaffolding and uncovering mosacis in B Bay and other bays of the gallery
      - Gregory, William John, "Diary of Work II", September 11, 1937 - November 20, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-069; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule and south gallery
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Note Book (Rejected), April 24, 1934 - November 14, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-070; 1 folder
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule, narthex, and lunettes; descriptions of tesserae colours and patterns; and observations of plaster at the south gallery
      - Gregory, William John, "Vestibule", April 28, 1934 - November 17, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-071; 1 folder
      - Gregory, William John, "Observation Book - I", April 28, 1934 - September 5, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-072; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Work conducted in the southwest vestibule panel and mosaics of the south gallery, and narthex
      - Gregory, William John, "Observation Book - II", September 6, 1934 - November 20, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-073; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Descriptions of work at the south gallery
      - Lye, Albert H., "Diary of Work", April 21, 1934 - November 21, 1934, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-074; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Daily Journal of Work at St. Sophia"
      - Coe, M. (possibly), "Various Notes on Narthex", Unknown, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-075; 1 folder
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notebook I: Notes of St. Sophia [and] Work on the mosacis of St. Sophia Museum, May 4, 1935 - July 31, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-076; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notebook II: Notes of St. Sophia [and] Work on the mosacis of St. Sophia Museum, August 1, 1935 - October 14, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-077; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes St. Sophia Museum I", May 4, 1935 - July 31, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-078; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Title from first page: "Notes taken at St. Sophia"
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes II: Notes of work 'John' Panel", August 1, 1935 - October 14, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-079; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Observation Book I: OBSERVATIONS MADE AT JOHN PANEL, DEISES, AND VESTIBULE PANEL", June 1, 1935 - September 17, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-080; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Observation Book II: OBSERVATIONS MADE JOHN PANEL, SOUTH GALLERY", September 17, 1935 - November 2, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-081; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Observation Book: Observations made of work on the John panel, Desises and Vestibule panel", June 1, 1935 - October 18, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-082; 1 folder
      - Gregory, William John, "Diary of Work St. Sophia I", May 4, 1935 - September 15, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-083; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Descriptions of Zoe and the Deësis panels
      - Gregory, William John, "Diary of Work (continued) II", September 16, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-084; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Notebook includes a postcard with the annotation: "St. Michael Love & Best Wishes to You Both From Dad."
      - Gregory, William John, "Book of Observations St. Sophia I", May 4, 1935 - September 22, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-085; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Description and drawings of the Zoe and Deësis panels in the south gallery and apse
      - Gregory, William John, "Book of Observations (continued) II", September 23, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-086; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Description and drawings of the apse
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Notebook I (Diary from front of book and observations from centre of book)", May 4, 1935 - May 28, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-087; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 6
        Description and drawings of the Zoe and southwest vestibule panels
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Notes II (Diary from front of book and observations from centre of book)", May 29, 1935 - June 20, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-088; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 6
        Description and drawings of the Zoe panel
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Notes III (Diary from front of book and observations from centre of book)", June 21, 1935 - July 25, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-089; 1 folder with notebook 3 of 6
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Notes IV (Diary from front of book and observations from centre of book)", July 26, 1935 - September 3, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-090; 1 folder with notebook 4 of 6; The 5th notebook in this series is missing.
      - Gregory, William John, "Rough Notes VI (Diary from front of book and observations from centre of book)", October 15, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-091; 1 folder with notebook 6 of 6; The 5th notebook in this series is missing
        Description of the apse and John panel
      - Gregory, William John, "Sketch Book (Diary)", May 27, 1935 - August 14, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-092; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Drawings of cramps, the Deësis panel, and sections of the mosaics
      - Gregory, William John, "Sketch Book (Observations)", May 30, 1935 - September 20, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-093; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
      - Gregory, William John, "Chart of Cramps placed in Apse", August 14, 1935 - November 8, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-094; 1 folder
      - Gregory, William John, "Book Tabulating Boxes of Samples", 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-095; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Tabulation of Sample Boxes"
      - Hatcher, H.S., "Rough Note Book", May 4, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-096; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Title from first page: "Rough Notes"
        Descriptions and drawings of the John Panel and south gallery
        H.S. Hatcher was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1935
        Hatcher, H.S.
      - Hatcher, H.S., "NOTEBOOK I", May 4, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-097; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Descriptions of cramp locations and measurements, the Deësis panel, and the south gallery
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "Notes on John Comnenus Panel (Central figure, John and Irene), 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-098; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Drawings and descriptions of the John panel in Russian. The date stamp on the notebook is November 1, 1935.
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "Notes on John Comnenus Panel (Alexius), 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-099; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Drawings and descriptions of the John panel in Russian.
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "Zoe and Constantine Mosaic", 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-100; 1 folder
      - Kluge, Nicholas, "The Deisis Mosaic", 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-101; 1 folder
      - Lye, Albert H., "Diary of Work", May 4, 1935 - November 1, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-102; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Daily Journal of Work at the Museum of St. Sophia"
        Descriptions of work conducted in the narthex, southwest vestibule, and apse
      - White, Alec Thomas, "Rough Note Book I: NOTES OF WORK IN ST. SOPHIA", May 4, 1935 - July 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-103; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Alec Thomas White was a Byzantine Institute field worker at Hagia Sophia, ca. 1935
        White, Alec Thomas
      - White, Alec Thomas, "Rough Note Book II", July 13, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-104; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Descriptions and drawings of work conducted in the south gallery, Zoe and Deësis panels
      - White, Alec Thomas, "Diary of Work I", May 4, 1935 - July 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-105; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
        Descriptions and drawings of work conducted at the south gallery, Zoe and Deësis panels
      - White, Alec Thomas, "Diary of Work I", June 4, 1935 - November 12, 1935, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-106; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
        Descriptions and drawings of work conducted at the south gallery and apse, and drawings of cramps
      - White, Alex Thomas, "Drawing Book No. 1 (Apse), Unknown, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-107; 1 folder
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Note Book: NOTES ON WORK AT ST. SOPHIA", May 5, 1936 - July 4, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-108; 1 folder
        Descriptions and drawings of work conducted on the Deësis, John, and Zoe panels
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes on Work at St. Sophia", May 5, 1936 - August 31, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-109; 1 folder with notebook 1 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Notes on Work at St. Sophia (Soffit Arch and Zoe Panel)", September 1, 1936 - October 14, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-110; 1 folder with notebook 2 of 2
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Observation Book", May 9, 1936 - July 4, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-111; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Observations of Work at St. Sophia"
        Descriptions and drawings of work conducted in the apse and south gallery
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Rough Notes", May 26, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-112; 1 folder
        Detailed account of the motion picture films taken on May 26, 1936
        For related motion picture films, see Subgroup 2, Series 4, Subseries 6, "Moving Images (16 mm)." Motion picture films have been reformatted and are available online: http://www.doaks.org/library-archives/icfa/special-projects/moving-image-collection/hagia-sophia
      - Gregory, Richard A., "Position of Work Day by Day", June 15, 1936 - October 15, 1936, MS.BZ.004-02-01-02-113; 1 folder